Are you investigating this case as a serial murder?
你们会将此案当作 连环谋杀案来调查吗？
It's too early to confirm that.
现在下定论还为时尚早
As you know,
正如各位所知
these murders took place in different districts.
这些谋杀案发生的地点都不相同
It's been over a month since the Suseong-dong incident.
寿城洞事件已经过去一个多月了
You still haven't made any progress?
还是毫无进展吗？
The detectives in those districts and the Special Crime Squad
机搜队和地方警察
are doing their best.
正在竭尽全力
Are you sure this isn't a serial murder?
确定不是连环谋杀案吗？
Everyone, please.
各位记者们
Don't jump to conclusions.
请不要妄下定论
You'll only scare the public.
你们这样只会让公众陷入恐慌
I heard the MO for all three cases was the same.
我听说三起案件的作案手法完全一致
And your answer is still a no?
你们还要否认吗？
Just look at these murders.
看看这些案子
Are you sure there weren't any accomplices?
你们确定没有共犯吗？
Is there a reason behind not treating this as a serial murder?
有什么理由说它不是连环谋杀案呢？
Since the incidents took place in different districts,
这些案子发生在不同地区
they couldn't have been a one-man job.
所以不可能是一人所为
You dropped this.
你把这个弄丢了
-I'm sorry. -Jeez.
-对不起 -真是的
What's going on?
怎么了？
Here it is.
在这里
Hello?
喂？
It's an alarm.
是闹钟啊
Just last September,
就在9月
there were three break-ins that led to murders.
三起入室抢劫演变成了谋杀案
But the police still haven't found a suspect
但警方仍未找到嫌犯
-Kitty, slow down. Okay? -which is alarming the public.
-小猫咪 慢点吃 -这使公众感到担忧
The police announced that they are taking various approaches
警方声称他们正在尝试各种方法
to investigate these three murder cases.
调查这三起谋杀案件
Some people are suggesting
部分媒体认为
that the culprit targeted wealthy senior citizens.
罪犯的目标是富足的老年人
But the police stated that grouping individual cases into one serial case
但警方指出将几个单独案件说成
was a risky move.
连环谋杀案是非常冒险的
-Without any definitive proof, -Take this.
-在没有任何确凿证据之前 -带上这个
-the police dispatched -What's that?
-警方派出了 -那是什么？
more resources to question more people and focus more on legwork.
更多警力进行询问调查 到处奔走
-But they haven't found a lead yet. -Okay.
-但目前仍无大的进展 -好的
The police are open to other possibilities
警方会考虑其他可能性
such as robberies or crimes of passion by the victims' acquaintances.
比如谋财或熟人仇杀等
And the police are following up on other possibilities.
同时警方也在跟进其他的可能性
Listen. Detectives like us
听着 我们这些警察
who do all the legwork catch the culprits.
为了抓捕罪犯累的像狗一样
When we were canvassing
我们在这些街区排查
these neighborhoods to the point that we got blisters,
脚都磨起水泡的时候
what did those district cops do?
那些地区警察都做了什么呀？
Yes. I'm glad you brought that up. Where were you in all of this?
没错 你说得对 那你干吗去了？
Right. You were at a sauna.
对了 你在桑拿房啊
I went there once!
我就去了一次！
Yes. I know that.
没错 我知道
You went to the sauna once, the go club once,
你去了一次桑拿房 去了一次夜店
and the Internet cafe once.
还去了一次网吧
Are you having fun playing computer games with high schoolers when you're 40?
你都40岁了 和高中生一起 打电脑游戏 好玩吗？
Do you think she's the type to tell on people?
你觉得她是那种告状的人吗？
You punk. I have ears too.
你个混小子 我也是有耳朵的
I think it's necessary to set boundaries between our squad and the Analysis Team.
我认为我们的小队有必要 和分析组划清界限
Right. That's my point.
对啊 我就是这个意思
They just wear suits and act all cool.
他们只知道穿着西装耍帅
They just have meetings like some scholars.
除了像学究一样开几个会
What do you think they can do?
他们还能做什么？
As long as they can pinpoint a suspect,
只要他们能查出嫌犯
it doesn't matter if they have meetings like scholars or standing on their heads.
随便他们是像学究那样开会 还是倒立什么的
What do you care?
你操什么心？
Entering the crime scene as they please is obstructing the investigation.
随意进入案发现场是妨碍调查
Captain Kook isn't Chief of Forensics anymore.
国组长已经不是鉴定股长了
And Song Ha-young was always into playing the hero.
宋霞永却总是喜欢充英雄
He keeps crossing the line. You know how he is.
他一直在越界 你是知道他的
I won't participate in making personal attacks.
你对他的个人评价待会儿再说
What?
什么？
Other teams aren't happy with the Behavioral Analysis Team.
其他小组对犯罪行为分析组 也都心怀不满
If there are no boundaries between us and them,
如果我们之间没有界限的话
whenever we get cases, there's bound to be conflict.
只要一有案子 我们就会起冲突
Listen.
不是
They are taking the lead on their own.
他们都是在凭自己的意志行动
-How can I stop them? -Gosh.
-我怎么阻止？ -天啊
Besides, they aren't really getting in your way.
而且他们也没有完全妨碍你
They can actually help you out.
其实他们可以帮到你
Goodness. Did you all have coffee this morning?
天啊 你们上午都喝过咖啡了吗？
-Hello, sir. -Hello.
-您好 -你们好
Come on! What's the matter with you?
拜托！你是怎么了？
What's going on in there?
里面在干什么？
It's too early to be yelling at this hour.
一大早就大吼大叫的
Well, the thing is…
这个嘛
Yesterday, when Chief Kim Bong-sik
金奉植股长昨天
went to check out the area in Jinjung-dong,
去晋中洞那带检查的时候
he ran into Inspector Song.
遇到了宋警卫
Darn it, that little…
见鬼 该死
Gosh.
天啊
-It's… -Captain Yoon and I
-这是… -我和尹组长
also run into him whenever we go to Suseong-dong or Gungok-dong.
无论是去寿城洞还是郡谷洞 也都会遇见他
It seems like Inspector Song is visiting all the scenes on a daily basis,
看来宋警卫每天都会去查看现场
so people are talking.
大家都是这么说的
-Captain Yoon. -Yes, sir.
-尹组长 -嗯
As police officers, it is our job to catch criminals.
抓捕罪犯是我们做警察的职责
Whether he's trying to play a hero or not,
无论他是否想充英雄
let's not doubt his genuine intentions.
我们就别再怀疑他的真心了
I don't doubt his intentions.
我没有怀疑
-Hello, sir. -What's going on?
-您好 -怎么了？
The Behavioral Analysis Team reports directly to me.
犯罪行为分析组是我直接管辖的
What's your problem?
你们有什么不满意的吗？
If you have a problem, talk to me.
有不满意的地方 就来找我说
It's not a big deal, sir. There was a misunderstanding.
不是什么大事 误会而已
Ban the Analysis Team from entering the scenes.
请禁止分析组进入现场吧
Oh, that's what you want?
你就想要这个？
That's it?
就这样吗？
Sure, fine.
好的 没问题
If you have a problem with that,
如果你介意此事的话
I'll be sure to let them know.
我一定会明确地告诉他们的
-Thank you, sir. -But the thing is,
-谢谢您 -但是
I can't stop them if they want to conduct their own investigation.
如果他们想要自己开展调查的话 我并不能阻止他们
They're cutting down on sleep to do that
他们牺牲休息时间
on top of conscientiously completing their own tasks,
以求认真完成自己的任务
so I can't tell them not to do that.
我不能阻止他们那么做
I can't dictate how much sleep they get.
我不能命令他们休息多少时间
Right, they're not kids.
那是当然 他们也不是什么小孩了
We're not asking you to just go ahead and stop them.
我们不是要叫您去阻止他们
The Analysis Team needs to understand that they're not an investigation team.
可分析组得明白 他们不是调查小组
Right, I also think…
没错 我也这么…
What's going on?
什么情况？
Hurry to the scene in Hwanghwa-dong.
请立刻赶往黄花洞现场
A senior citizen was murdered. Hurry to the scene at once.
一位老人被杀害 请立刻赶往现场
-Let's hurry. -Come on.
-我们快点 -快
Oh, I see. Got it.
好的 我知道了
-It's urgent. -Okay.
-事出紧急 -明白
It's in Hwanghwa-dong!
是在黄花洞！
Come on.
快点
-Hey, get the car ready! -Yes, sir!
-喂 备好车子！ -收到！
SEOUL METROPOLITAN POLICE AGENCY
（首尔地方警察厅）
Gosh, I didn't know that so many people were into hiking.
天啊 我不知道有那么多人爬山
I did this all day yesterday, and I don't see an end in sight.
昨天我干了一整天 简直望不到头
I'll become a hiking expert at this rate.
照这样下去 我都快成登山专家了
Hey, those in Forensics have it way worse.
喂 鉴定组的人比我们惨多了
Their hands have already turned into feet,
他们的手都快变成脚了
so they walk on all fours now. Like this.
他们现在用四肢爬行 像这样
Can't you laugh even if it's not funny?
就算不滑稽也不能笑一笑吗？
Did he have to storm out like that?
他就非得那样冲出去吗？
What would you like for lunch?
你午饭想吃什么呢？
You've gotten quite brazen, Chu Chu.
翅膀硬了啊 宙宙
SPECIAL CRIME SQUAD 1
（机动搜查队一科）
Did something happen?
出什么事了吗？
Another senior citizen was murdered in Hwanghwa-dong.
又有一名老人在黄花洞遇害了
They all went to the scene a little while ago.
他们刚刚都去现场了
Goodness. Hey! Get it done properly!
天啊 喂！都小心点！
-Sir, you can't come in here. -Why not?
-您不能走这边了 -为什么？
-Go the other way. -This is crazy.
-走别的路吧 -这太疯狂了
-Go the other way! -Darn it.
-走别的路吧！ -见鬼
I didn't mean to offend you.
我不是故意冒犯你的
I just said to go the other way. Gosh, this is so frustrating.
我说让你换条路走 真是太烦人了
Guys, keep the residents out.
伙计们 管理好居民们
-Sir! You can't come in here. -Why not?
-先生！您不能进去 -为什么？
This is nuts.
这太疯狂了
You can't come in here.
你不能进来这里
-You can't come in here. -Gosh. Move.
-你不能进 -天啊 闪开
Gosh, what is this?
天啊 这是什么？
Chief! You can't touch that. You know you can't touch anything here.
股长 不能碰 你知道这里的东西你都不能碰
We're still trying to lift prints.
我们还在收集指纹
-You can't touch that. -You can't come in here.
-你不能碰那里 -你不能进来这里
-No, stop! -My goodness.
-不行 住手！ -我的天啊
-Don't touch anything. -Darn it.
-什么都别碰 -见鬼
-Get out. -Get rid of this stench first, idiot!
-出去 -先通风啊 笨蛋！
-You're contaminating the scene. -Darn it. Let go!
-你在破坏现场 -见鬼 放手！
Gosh.
天啊
-There he is. -Hey.
-他出来了 -喂
Hey, how did the fire break out?
喂 怎么会发生火灾？
The culprit tried to set the house on fire.
犯人试图放火烧了整个屋子
Thankfully, it died out after burning a part of the body and the ceiling.
还好火势减弱了 只烧毁了尸体的一部分和屋顶
Then maybe it was someone else.
那就有可能是别的罪犯吧
We'd have to look into it further, but a blunt weapon was used.
我们得进一步调查 不过用的是钝器
The triangle again?
又是三角形？
FORENSICS
（鉴定 警察）
Gosh, this is insane.
天啊 真是疯了
What is happening?
究竟怎么回事？
Then why did he start the fire?
那他为什么要纵火呢？
Maybe there was something he wanted to hide.
可能他想隐藏什么东西
We're looking into that too.
对此我们也正在调查
I'll collect statements from the bereaved at the station.
我要去警察局拿家属陈诉了
Okay, sure.
嗯 好的
How long will this take?
我们要等多久？
There was a fire, so I'd say about ten hours.
因为发生过火灾 我想得要十小时吧
What's Kim Bong-sik doing inside?
金奉植在里面做什么？
I have no idea. Why is he…
我不知道 他为什么…
I'll lift all his prints and submit them as evidence.
我会把他的指纹都采集回去当证据
-Darn it. -All right, I'm sorry.
-见鬼 -对不起
-Keep it up. -Get back to work.
-继续吧 -回去干活
-Thank you.
-辛苦了 -谢谢
-What is going on? -Hey.
-发生了什么？ -喂
-Gil-pyo. -Yes.
-吉票 -嗯
I told you not to smoke and contaminate the scenes.
我告诉过你不要在现场抽烟搞破坏
I'm just frustrated. They said it'd take ten hours.
我就是太郁闷了 他们说得花十小时
Frustrated, my foot. How many of these did we find last time?
郁闷你个头 上次我们找到了多少？
Do you want to end up on the list of suspects again?
你又想被举证为疑犯吗？
-Are you here to nag me or what? -Whatever. Anyway, what happened?
-你是来这里唠叨我的吗？ -随你怎么说 不过究竟发生了什么？
It's being investigated now.
目前仍在调查
We're waiting too.
我们也在等
You guys in the Analysis Team should return to the office.
你们分析小组的人应该回办公室去
-How can we return to the office? -Gosh, seriously.
-我们怎么回去办公室？ -天啊 真是的
Captain Kook.
国组长
Chief Kim Bong-sik is inside.
金奉植股长在里面
He's inside?
他在里面？
-Kim Bong-sik, this little… -Hey, stop.
-金奉植这个小子… -喂 别进去
This is wrong.
这样不妥
You're no longer in the Forensics Squad.
你已经从鉴定组出来了
You know that Kim Bong-sik likes to talk.
你知道金奉植很会嚼舌根
Look, many eyes are watching.
看看吧 周围那么多双眼睛盯着呢
If people start to complain about your team frequenting the scenes,
如果大家开始对你小组的人 频繁进出现场有所抱怨的话
things will get complicated for all of us.
事情对大家而言只会变得更复杂
Both you and Superintendent Baek are here.
你和白科长都在这里
Why should I walk on eggshells around him?
我为什么要看他的脸色？
We can't have your back forever.
我们没法一直替你撑腰啊
The two teams must respect each other's boundaries.
两组人马必须彼此尊重对方的底线
You were the one who came up with this system.
这可是你提出来的机制啊
Exactly. Just go back to the office and wait.
没错 快回去办公室等着吧
We'll share all the updates with you.
我们会把新消息全部告诉你的
Why must we argue about this now?
为什么我们非得现在争论这些？
-Just go back to the office. -I'm so angry right now.
-快回办公室 -我现在太生气了
Why is he standing there alone, looking all serious?
他怎么又一个人那么严肃地站在那？
Let's go for a smoke.
我们去一起抽根烟吧
Sure, let's go.
好 走吧
-Go somewhere far. -I can smoke over there, right?
-走远点 -我能在这里抽烟吗？
-Not within a 50m-radius. -All right.
-50米开外才行 -好吧
-There must've been an arson attempt. -Yes, there's the burning smell.
-一定有人企图纵火 -对 有股烧焦的气味
Who's the victim?
受害人是谁？
A female in her 60s.
一名60多岁的女性
A quiet alley in an affluent residential area.
人迹罕至的一条安静小巷
I don't see a single security camera.
看不到一个监控摄像头
But an arson attempt. That's a first.
而且还试图纵火 这是头一回
It was premeditated, right?
有预谋的吧？
Yes. But something is off.
是 好像哪里不对劲
What's odd?
哪里不对劲？
The first incident took place on September 12.
第一次事故发生在9月12号
The second one on the 24th. The third one on the 30th.
第二次24号 第三次30号
The interval between the cases has gone down from 12 to 6 days.
案件发生的间隔期 从12天缩短到了6天
But it has increased to a month.
可这次又增加到了一个月
If this really is a premeditated serial murder case,
如果真的是有预谋的连环谋杀案
such decreased intervals and sporadic patterns
这种减少间隔和偶发的作案模式
mean that the killer is becoming bolder.
意味着凶手的胆子在变大
However, it took the killer a month to commit this murder.
可是凶手在一个月后才再次作案
There must've been a reason.
背后一定有原因
What could it be?
不过会是什么呢？
Was it suicide?
是自杀吗？
What caused the fire? Was it attempted arson?
是什么导致的火灾？是故意纵火吗？
-Move back. -Did the fire kill the victim?
-后退 -大火烧死了受害人吗？
-Or was it murder? -Move back!
-还是说这是起谋杀案？ -后退！
-Have you identified a suspect? -Yoon Tae-gu from Seoul HQ?
-你们确认疑犯了吗？ -首尔总部的尹泰九？
There have been many murders lately. What's your plan?
近来谋杀案频发 你们有对应的计划吗？
Was the victim murdered?
受害者是被谋杀的吗？
Just a comment, please!
请说几句吧！
-What exactly happened? -Tell us!
-到底发生了什么？ -告诉我们吧！
-Is this a homicide case?
-这是起杀人案吗？
Earlier today, at around 11:10 a.m. on Thursday, October 30,
今天是10月30号 星期四 大约在上午10点左右
Yoon Jung-yoon, a 65-year-old female,
尹正允 一名65岁的女性
was found dead in her home in Hwanghwa-dong, Seoul.
被发现在首尔黄花洞的家中遇害
She was attacked with a blunt weapon.
她被钝器所伤
Her husband, Han Jong-yong,
她的丈夫韩钟镛
saw that their house was filled with smoke
在下班回家后
upon returning home from work
发现家中烟雾弥漫
and called it in.
就此报警
What was used to start the fire?
火灾是如何引起的？
We believe that the culprit used
我们认为罪犯是用
newspaper and paper to start the fire.
新闻报纸之类的东西纵火的
Any lead on the culprit?
找到任何有关罪犯的线索了吗？
We can't tell you anything at the moment.
我们目前无可奉告
We're restricting access to the scene
事发现场已经严格管控
as we wait for the Forensics Squad's preliminary results,
目前仍在等待鉴定组的初步调查结果
so I hope you understand we can't share any details with you at the moment.
因此我们目前无法告知各位 任何细节 希望大家给予理解
Were any cash or valuables stolen from the scene?
现场有任何现金或贵重物品被偷吗？
How did she get in here?
她是怎么进去的呢？
At the moment,
目前
it doesn't seem like anything was stolen.
尚未发现有任何东西被偷
Do you still think it was done by an acquaintance of the victim?
您是否还坚持认为 凶手是受害者的熟人？
We are considering every possibility.
我们正在考虑每一种可能性
As I mentioned earlier,
正如我先前所言
we're still waiting for the preliminary results--
我们还在等待初步调查结果…
Do you admit that this may be connected to the cases
您是否承认这起案件 可能与寿城洞、郡谷洞
that occurred in Suseong-dong, Gungok-dong, and Jinjung-dong?
和晋中洞发生的 那几起案件有关联呢？
Serial murders targeting affluent senior citizens.
连环谋杀案的目标是富有的老年人
Do you admit it?
您承认这点吗？
Well about that…
这个嘛
We plan to expand the investigation keeping in mind
我们计划扩大调查范围
the possibility that the culprit could be the same person.
并考虑罪犯可能是同一个人
Do you think there was an accomplice like the Jijon Family case?
是否有可能像至尊派案件一样 有共犯存在呢？
There wasn't any accomplice?
难道没有任何帮凶吗？
Are they related?
这些案件相关吗？
-Do you have any speculations? -Are the cases related?
-您有什么想法吗？ -案件之间有关联吗？
Excuse me, reporters. I apologize.
抱歉 各位记者
I'm sure you have more questions,
我知道你们还有很多问题
but that's all for today's briefing.
但今天的发布会到此结束
We will do our best to arrest the culprit,
我们会竭尽全力逮捕罪犯
so please give us some time.
请给我们一些时间
Thank you.
谢谢
-Where are you going? -That's it?
-您要去哪里？ -这就结束了？
-Are those done by the same guy? -Is everything related?
-是同一个家伙干的吗？ -所有事之间都有关联吗？
Breaking news.
来看一则快讯
This morning, a woman in her sixties was found dead
今天在黄花洞一处居民区
in a residential area in Hwanghwa-dong.
发现一名60多岁的女性尸体
The police launched an investigation.
警方展开调查
The police believe these cases of wealthy elderly murders
警方认为几起谋杀富有老人的案件
were possibly planned as serial murders.
很有可能是计划好的连环谋杀案
The police identified the culprit of the Hwanghwa-dong incident
警方确认了此次黄花洞事件的凶手
as the same one who committed the three previous murders of the elderly.
就是之前三起谋杀老人案的凶手
They repeatedly stated they would expand the investigation
他们强调会将其作为连环谋杀案
to a serial murder case.
以扩大调查范围
DAEHAN DAILY
《大韩日报》
POLICE ADMITS ELDERLY MURDERS AS SERIAL KILLING
（警方承认此案为 以富有老人为目标的连环杀人案）
FORENSICS
（鉴定 警察）
Why did he suddenly start a fire?
为什么他会突然放火？
He's never done that before.
他之前从没那么干过
Did you find any inflammable?
你找到任何易燃物了吗？
-Check out this area first. -All right.
-先来看这里吧 -好的
He didn't prepare anything in particular.
他没做什么特别的准备
I think it started with a newspaper.
我想大火就是由报纸点燃的
If he didn't bring any inflammable,
如果他没带任何易燃物
I don't think he sought after
我认为他不像大多数纵火犯那样
psychological exhilaration as most arsonists do.
寻求心理上的快感
If he was after psychological exhilaration,
如果他是为了获得心理快感
he would've stayed and watched the fire grow.
他就会留下来看着火势变大
You're right.
你说得没错
I'm sure he came across an unexpected situation.
他肯定遇到了意外情况
He either wanted to destroy unwanted traces
他要么是为了毁掉多余的痕迹
or it could've been his trace.
要么就是为了抹掉自己的痕迹
He failed to open the safe.
他没能打开保险柜
Maybe this was a copycat crime.
可能是起模仿犯罪
He wasn't keen on taking the valuables until now.
直到现在他才想起要拿些贵重物品
But he used the same weapon.
可他用的是同一种凶器
Triangular?
三角形？
Then let's check the body first.
那就先来确认尸体吧
He destroyed the cross.
他毁掉了十字架
An unnecessary act.
这是多余行迹
Mallet. Hammer. Brick.
棒槌 榔头 砖块
We took everything we could find
我们找遍了所有可以想到的工具
to see if any of them could leave a triangular mark,
想尝试留下三角形的伤口
but none of them did.
但没有一个是可行的
Do you think he made the weapon himself?
你觉得他会是自己做的吗？
The murder weapon?
杀人凶器吗？
I mean, we can't seem to find it.
那为什么我们就是找不到凶器呢？
His choice of a blunt weapon rather than a sharp one
他选择钝器而不是利刃的理由是
shows the anger built within the culprit.
为了表达罪犯内心的愤慨
What made him become this furious
是什么让他变得如此狂暴
to brutally kill complete strangers?
以至于要这样残杀陌生人呢？
-Let's check. -May I borrow a notebook?
-我们开始检查吧 -我能借一下笔记本吗？
-Thank you. -First off, the front.
-谢谢 -首先是前面
One, two, three, four.
一、二、三、四
On the head, one…
在头部 一…
He isn't after money.
他不是为了钱财
It wasn't done by an acquaintance who holds a grudge.
也不是一个怀恨在心的熟人干的
In that case,
那样的话
where did his anger that ultimately made him attack
让他最终攻击这些无助的
these helpless wealthy victims stem from?
富有受害者的愤怒又是从何而来呢？
Are you sure?
你确定吗？
Last night,
昨晚
he wanted to put that jacket on, but he changed into something else,
他想穿那件夹克衫的 不过后来他换了其他衣服
then left it on the sofa before he left.
走之前把夹克衫留在了沙发上
But come morning,
但第二天早上
the jacket was gone.
夹克衫不见了
Maybe the victim moved it somewhere.
可能是受害者把它放到别的地方去了
So I asked the chief of Forensics to find it first.
所以我让鉴定股长先找到它
He looked for it twice, but it wasn't there.
他找了两遍都没找到
He left the money and valuables.
凶手放着钱财和贵重物品不拿
All he took was a black jacket?
偏要拿一件夹克衫？
It suddenly got chilly this morning.
今天早上忽然变冷了
This is such a shame.
真是可惜啊
If we had cameras in the alleys, we would've found him by now.
如果巷子里都有摄像头的话 我们现在就能找到他了
We put up many more at the beginning of this year.
今年年初我们不是装了很多吗？
When we never had them, I never thought about it,
在没有摄像头的时期 我是没有一点想法的
but I guess I began to feel this way now that we have some.
但可能是因为我们有了一些 我才会这么想的吧
They're making the control center next year.
明年他们会成立一个中央监管中心
Hopefully, things will change.
还是挺期待的
Over there.
那里有
They're all wearing black.
他们都穿着黑衣服
But it's just a day's worth.
可这只是一天的量
-Find someone in hiking boots. -Okay.
-找找穿登山鞋的人 -好的
He carried a big weapon around, so I'll find someone with a backpack too.
他还带着大件武器到处走 所以我也会注意有背包的人
Once you screen them,
你筛选出疑犯后
ask the husband if it's the jacket he lost.
就去问那家丈夫 夹克衫是不是他丢掉的那件
Yes.
好的
Goodness, Reporter Im Moo-sik.
天啊 林武植记者
I always gave you the information.
我一直都在告诉你消息
If we find anything, I'll let you know first.
如果我们找到了什么 我会第一时间告诉你的
Hey, wait.
喂 等一下
Why? Did you find something?
怎么了？你发现什么了吗？
GUNGOK-DONG, HWANGHWA-DONG
（郡谷洞 黄花洞）
Man, look at this guy.
天啊 看看这个家伙
SUSEONG-DONG, JINJUNG-DONG
（寿城洞 晋中洞）
-I'll call you back. -One second.
-我晚点打给你 -等一下
Gil-pyo!
吉票！
-This jerk. -What? Did you find anything?
-这个混蛋 -什么？你找到线索了吗？
Listen up.
听着
Suseong.
寿城
Gungok.
郡谷
Jinjung. Hwanghwa.
晋中 黄花
-What about them? -They have the same consonants.
-它们怎么了？ -它们的辅音都相同啊
Darn it. Explain it so that I can understand.
见鬼 快给我解释清楚
Suseong. S and S.
寿城 S和S
Gungok. G and G.
郡谷 G和G
-Jinjung. -J and J.
-晋中 -J和J
-Hwanghwa. -H and H!
-黄花 -H和H
Look, they are all located in places with good access.
看 它们都位于交通便利的地方
Not only are there luxurious residential districts,
不仅是豪华的住宅区
but the towns also have a concentrated area of adult entertainment businesses
这些还都是成人娱乐业的集中地
that are accessible by public transport.
交通非常便利
So what?
所以呢？
The investigation team says he must've gone around in a car
调查小组说罪犯一定有辆车
because he was never seen
因为尽管他在一大片地区实施犯罪
even though he committed the crimes in a large area.
他却从未被人看到过
But it might be the opposite.
但情况也可能正好相反
Oh, he uses public transit?
他乘坐公共交通工具吗？
In-tak said there's a jacket missing, right?
仁卓说有件夹克衫丢了吗？
Yes, if that's true, it's another proof for our second theory.
是的 如果情况属实 那就证明了我们的第二个猜想
The temperature dropped this morning,
今天早上降温了
so if he didn't have a car, he would've needed a jacket or something.
所以如果他没有车的话 他会需要一件夹克衫之类的外套
We can make another assumption.
我们也可以做另一个假设
What is it?
什么假设？
He could've needed to hide his bloodstained clothes.
他得把他沾满血渍的衣服藏起来
If that's the case,
如果是那样的话
then shouldn't we have many more witnesses?
我们不就有更多的目击证人了吗？
I mean, he used public transit.
如果他乘坐公共交通工具的话
Even if he went around with bloodstained clothes,
就算他穿着带有血迹的衣服出门
most people wouldn't have noticed
大多数人也都不会注意的
unless they saw him near the crime scene.
除非他们在犯罪现场附近见过他
Right, you're right.
没错 你说得对
He wouldn't go around telling people he's a murderer.
他不会到处告诉人们他是凶手
Also, surprisingly,
而且令人意外的是
people aren't too interested in others.
人们对他人并不在意
Due to their inattentiveness,
由于他们的疏忽
they wouldn't get suspicious nor perceive it as strange
正如黄大顺所言 即便人们看到了他血迹斑斑的衣服
even if they saw his bloody clothes, just as Hwang Dae-sun said.
他们也不会怀疑或觉得奇怪的
Right.
没错
GUNGOK-DONG, HWANGHWA-DONG, SUSEONG-DONG, JINJUNG-DONG
（郡谷洞 黄花洞 寿城洞 晋中洞）
RESTRICTED AREA AUTHORIZED PERSONNEL ONLY
（闲杂人等 禁止入内）
That man. Is that the jacket?
那个人 是那件夹克衫吗？
Hello?
喂？
Yes, Chief.
是的 股长
CHIEF OH IN-TAK OF FORENSICS
（吴仁卓鉴定股长）
To sum up, the culprit probably doesn't have a car,
结论就是罪犯可能没有车
and he's a guy with a shoe size between 260mm to 265mm?
他的鞋子尺寸在42到43码之间
One second.
等一下
Hello, Captain Kook Young-soo of Behavioral Analysis…
喂 犯罪行为分析组组长国荣秀…
Hey, In-tak.
喂 仁卓啊
All right.
好的
Fax it over right away. Thanks.
现在就传真过来 多谢
We can stop looking for the shoes.
我们终于不用再找鞋子了
They found it?
他们找到了吗？
-Which brand is it? -He'll fax it to me.
-是什么牌子的？ -他会传真给我的
Wait, how does this make any sense?
等等 这像话吗？
Why doesn't it? It fits perfectly.
为什么不像话？这很合理啊
Have you found any evidence more trustworthy than this?
你能找出比这更有说服力的证据吗？
You should dispatch some men in Bangbae-dong.
你应该派人去方背洞
You need to stop the fifth murder!
你得阻止第五起谋杀案啊！
You're all here. Take a look at this.
你们都在这里 开看看这个
-What? -You found something?
-什么？ -你找到线索了吗？
The hiking shoes…
是登山鞋…
Why do you have this?
你怎么会有这个？
If you want to get cranky, you should do your job first.
你想发脾气的话 就先干好自己的活吧
I don't want any inconvenience either.
我也不想让大家觉得不便
What is it?
这是什么？
Darn it, the chief of Forensics is doing his job weirdly.
见鬼 鉴定股长的工作方式真古怪
Not as much as you, Chief.
没有你机搜队股长古怪吧
-What? -You're with the superintendent.
-什么？ -你们在科长面前做什么啊
-Okay. -Over here. This one.
-好吧 -在这里 就这个
We found him.
我们找到了
Yes, but you're a step too late.
嗯 不过你晚了一步
It's CCTV footage.
我是说监控录像
We got a shot of the back of the culprit.
我们拍到了罪犯的背影
What are we supposed to do with that?
我们该怎么处理这个？
We're still in a tight spot with or without leads.
不管有没有线索 我们的压力还是很大
We won't be able to find anything with that.
仅凭这个我们也找不出什么来
Come to the conference room.
快来会议室
We caught the back of the culprit on a security camera.
我们在监控录像里 抓拍到了罪犯的背影
Did you forget something?
你忘了什么吗？
-Should I go and fetch it now? -No. Wait.
-要我现在去帮你拿吗？ -不用 等一下
It's not his face. It's his back.
不是他的脸 而是背影
Right. Yes.
对 没错
Let's dispatch some people to Bangbae-dong.
我们派些人去方背洞吧
And why don't we interrogate those with the same shoes in the area?
那我们为什么不去审讯这附近 穿同样鞋子的人呢？
There will be countless people who own
光是在首尔
the same hiking shoes of the same size just in Seoul.
穿相同尺码徒步鞋的人就数不胜数
We won't be able to track people who bought them in cash.
我们无法找到用现金购买鞋子的人
We should start with the neighborhoods like we're taking a census.
我们应该从社区开始 就像我们做人口普查那样
I think doing the legwork will be better.
我觉得跑外勤更好
It's not just one neighborhood.
可这不止一个社区
As you know, these murders took place all over Seoul.
正如我们知道的 犯罪覆盖区域很广
Sir, why are we going to Bangbae-dong?
队长 为什么我们要去方背洞？
What? Oh, that?
什么？哦 那个嘛？
All right. Listen up.
好吧 听好了
Suseong. Gungok.
寿城 郡谷
Jinjung. Hwanghwa.
晋中 黄花
Anything?
没想法吗？
You idiots.
你们这些傻子
S and S. G and G.
S和S G和G
The syllables start with the same consonants.
这些音节都以相同的辅音开头啊
Let's put out an APB.
我们来发布全境通缉吧
What nonsense is that?
你在说什么胡话？
We must put out an APB.
我们必须发布公开通缉
How could we put out an APB with just that?
我们怎么能够仅凭这个 就发布公开通缉呢？
Come on in. You're here so join us.
进来吧 既然来了就一起讨论吧
And take us step by step.
让我们一步步来
We must broadcast it nationally on the nine o'clock news.
我们必须在《9点新闻》上 进行大量播报
He's driving me crazy. Come on.
他真要把我逼疯了
But we know nothing about the guy.
可我们对那个家伙一无所知
You want us to do that with the footage that shows his back?
你想让我们拿着一张监控录像里的 背影照片去公开通缉吗？
Having the footage of his back won't make any difference.
拿到他的背影照片并无多大用处
About 99 percent of the tips we receive won't be useful.
我们收到的约99%的举证都不会有用
Then it will only complicate our investigation.
那样只会让我们的调查变得更复杂
But while he keeps a low profile,
但如果他保持低调的话
we can buy time.
我们可以争取时间
I think it's a good idea.
我认为这是个好主意
The cooling-off period was long between the third and fourth cases because…
第三起和第四起案件之间 冷却期变长的原因在于…
Wait. What's a cooling-off period?
等等 什么是冷却期？
It's a hiatus for serial killers.
就是连环杀手们的空档期
Hey, he didn't ask you.
喂 他可没在问你
Come on.
真是的
It took a month for him to commit the fourth murder
他在一个月后才实施第四起谋杀案的
because of the press.
理由就是媒体
What about the press?
媒体怎么了？
Up to the third case, his cooling-off period was shortened
直到第三个案件 他的冷却期在变短
because he was confident.
因为他当时很自信
-What's going on? -But the press
-出什么事了？ -可是媒体
raised suspicions of serial murder.
对连环谋杀提出了怀疑
And they started to pay attention to each case individually.
于是他们开始关注每个独立的案件
The moment he became confident,
在他变得自信的时候
he hesitated in case he might get caught.
他也犹豫不决 怕被抓到
But he killed again.
可是他又杀人了
It means that the pleasure from killing
这就说明杀人给他带来的愉悦感
and his confidence overweighed his fear of getting caught.
及他的自信压倒了他对被抓的恐惧
You're saying that there could be another victim?
你是说可能会有其他受害者？
Yes. He only hesitated. He didn't stop.
没错 他只是在犹豫 他并没有停手
Even if he kills again, it won't be easy to catch him.
就算他重新杀人 也很难抓住他
That arrogant jerk.
那个傲慢的混蛋
Chief Kim Bong-sik.
金奉植股长
Do I have to teach you how to respect your colleagues?
需要我教你如何尊重同事吗？
He's aware of his crimes
他清楚自己的罪行
and our investigation progress.
以及我们的调查进度
He's smart.
他很聪明
Don't tell me you're buying this nonsense.
别跟我说你会信这种说辞
The culprit will watch the broadcast somewhere.
罪犯会在某个地方观看电视放送的
-He pays attention to the press. -So…
-他会关注媒体 -所以…
are you suggesting that we give him a warning
你是建议我们给他一点警告
that he could get caught?
告诉他我们能逮到他吗？
That's correct.
就是这样
He has already committed four murders.
他已经犯下四起谋杀案了
He won't stop here.
他不会就此罢手的
The only way to prevent him from committing the next murder…
阻止他犯下新的谋杀案的唯一方法
is this.
只有这个
Stop him from striking again…
阻止他再次杀人…
But we should consider this as making progress, right?
再怎么说 我们也算取得进展了吧？
We found the hiking shoes.
我们找到了徒步鞋
And we got his back on camera. I'm sure we'll find him soon.
我们还在监控上找到了他的背影 我相信我们很快就会抓到他了
Everyone is working together. He can't get away.
所有人都在一起努力 他跑不掉的
You're right.
你说得对
-Chu Chu, we'll give you a ride. -No. It's okay. I can take the bus.
-宇宙宙 我们载你一程吧 -没用了 没关系 我可以坐公交
-We have room. Let me drop you. -Yes.
-我们有空位 我带你回去吧 -对呀
No. It's in a different direction.
不是的 方向是反的
Taking the bus is more comfortable.
坐公交更舒服
Okay. I get it. You want to get away from us as soon as possible.
好吧 明白了 你就想快点摆脱我们
See you tomorrow.
明天见
-Okay. Goodnight. -Okay.
-好的 晚安 -好
-Get home safely. -Goodnight.
-路上注意安全 -晚安
-Bye.
-再见
MURDER CASES IN SUSEONG-DONG, GUNGOK-DONG, AND JINJUNG-DONG
（寿城洞、郡谷洞、晋中洞谋杀案）
MURDER CASE IN HWANGHWA-DONG
（黄花洞谋杀案）
Do you seriously believe putting out an APB will work?
你真的相信公开通缉有用吗？
Why not?
为什么没用？
With just that?
就凭那个吗？
You really should
你真的应该
learn to listen to your colleagues.
学一学如何倾听
What?
什么？
He wants to use this as a warning
他想以此警告罪犯
to stop the next murder.
别再继续谋杀他人
I thought everyone understood that.
我以为所有人都听懂了
But I guess you didn't.
看来不是啊
A warning? As if.
警告吗？说得跟真的一样
Do you think our duty is to scare people?
你以为警察是什么善导部吗？
If you can't understand this,
如果你无法理解这一点
following the majority is also a way.
随大流也是一种方法
Hey.
喂
I've been too nice to you. How dare you talk to me like that?
是我对你太好说话了吧 你竟敢这么跟我说话？
I really hope you will stop being nice to me.
我真希望您别再对我这么好说话了
Your personality hasn't changed one bit. I bet you'll live a long life. Right?
你的性格一点都没变 我打赌你会很长寿的 对吗？
What did you say?
你说什么？
I'm your fellow detective.
我是你的警察同事
But you still treat me like a woman.
可你还像对待一个女人一样对待我
Narrow-minded, shallow, biased, and immature.
狭隘、肤浅、有偏见 还不成熟
That's how your perception is.
这就是你的认知
And are you cool with ruffling up other people's feathers?
你就无所谓惹其他人生气吗？
You little…
你个混…
Did you see that?
看到了吧？
If you weren't a woman,
如果你不是个女人的话
I would have slapped you right away.
我早就扇你了
I'm not slapping you because you're a--
我不扇你就是因为你是个…
This is my answer…
对于你之前对我的所作所为
to what you did to me before.
这就是我的回应
I thought I was over it.
我以为我不会再计较了
I guess I wasn't.
看来并非如此啊
Hey, Yoon Tae-gu!
喂 尹泰九！
If you don't want to be treated like a woman,
如果你不想被当做女人来对待
cut your hair that you've insisted on growing for the victims!
就剪掉你那坚持为受害者留的长发！
Darn it!
该死的！
So I pushed for it.
所以我已经极力争取了
Do you think putting out an APB will work?
你觉得公开通缉会有用吗？
If he hides, it will be harder to find him.
要是他藏了起来 就更难找到他了
You have a point.
你说得有道理
But stopping the next murder is our top priority right now.
但我们目前的头等大事 是阻止他再次行凶
Right. That's true.
对 没错
Yes.
对吧？
Drop me off here.
让我在这里下车吧
-Here? -Yes.
-这里吗？ -对
-Good work. -Thanks. Bye.
-辛苦了 -好 再见
-See you tomorrow. -Okay.
-明天见 -好的
Gosh.
天啊
-Captain Kook. -Yes?
-国组长 -什么？
Hold on.
等一下
What?
怎么了？
Wait. I have something.
稍等 我有点东西
My mother gave it to me this morning. But I forgot about it all day. I'm sorry.
这是我妈今早给我的 可我忘了一天 实在抱歉
What is this? Why are you apologizing?
这是什么？你有什么好对不起的？
This is a present from me.
这是我给你的礼物
Happy birthday.
生日快乐
Me? Today is…
我？今天是…
Goodness.
天啊
Hey, I'm an old man. I don't need presents.
喂 我都那么老了 不需要什么礼物
People in our line of work only memorize crime dates.
干我们这行的只记得犯罪日期
We always forget birthdays.
我们总会忘记生日
Anyway, thank you.
总之谢谢你啊
And please thank your mother for me too.
也请替我向你的母亲道谢
-Sure. -You're making me blush.
-好的 -你都让我脸红了
-Gosh. Thanks. I mean it. -Sure.
-天啊 我真的太感激了 -没什么
Okay.
行
Song Ha-young is a nice gifter.
宋霞永很有眼光啊
Happy birthday to me.
祝我生日快乐
Oh, right.
对了
Sorry, honey.
对不起 老婆
-I… -Happy birthday, honey.
-我… -生日快乐啊 老公
-Happy birthday, Dad.
-爸爸 生日快乐
-Happy birthday to you
-祝你生日快乐
-Happy birthday to you, dear Dad -Happy birthday to you, dear my husband
-祝亲爱的爸爸生日快乐 -祝我亲爱的老公生日快乐
-Happy birthday to you
-祝你生日快乐
-Goodness. Thank you. -Make a wish now.
-天啊 谢谢你们 -现在许愿吧
Dad, you need to make a wish.
爸爸 你要许愿哦
Okay, hold on.
好的 等一下
-Did you do it? -What did you wish for?
-许好了吗？ -你许了什么愿望？
It's a secret.
这是个秘密
-Come on.
-真是的
I'm glad we got to wish you a happy birthday before midnight.
幸好我们在12点前就祝你生日快乐了
I know. Thank you.
我知道 谢谢你
-I love you. -I love you, Dad.
-我爱你 -我爱你 爸爸
Daddy's wish is…
爸爸的心愿是…
But we know nothing about the guy.
可我们对那个家伙一无所知
You want us to do that with the footage that shows his back?
就凭监控录像里一张背景照片 你就想叫我们发布公开通缉？
Having the footage of his back won't make any difference.
拿到录像里他的背影照片也无济于事
About 99 percent of the tips we receive won't be useful.
我们收到的99%的举证都不会有用的
Then it will only complicate our investigation.
这只会使我们的调查变得更加复杂
Do you think putting out an APB will work?
你觉得公开通缉会有用吗？
If he hides, it will be harder to find him.
如果他藏了起来 要找他就更难了
Did we make the right decision?
我们的决定没错吧？
PROFILING REPORT ON SUSEONG, GUNGOK, JINJUNG, AND HWANGHWA CASES
（寿城洞、郡谷洞、晋中洞和黄花洞 案件分析报告）
MURDER SUSPECT WANTED REWARD 50 MILLION WON
（凶杀嫌犯通缉 悬赏5000万韩元）
What if this just ends up complicating our investigation?
如果这让我们的调查复杂化怎么办？
-Send it right away. -I'm telling you. That's why.
-现在就发 -我告诉你 这就是原因
We will put out an APB.
我们会公开通缉的
Attention, please.
各位 请注意一下
Hold on a moment.
等一下
The phones will keep ringing off the hook.
以后电话就会一直响个不停
I know things will get hectic,
我明白事情会变得更复杂
but don't dismiss any info you obtain through these calls.
但是请不要忽视你通过这些电话 获得的任何信息
If you hear anything suspicious, let us know.
如果你们发现任何可疑的线索 都请告诉我们
Please remember that we must prioritize the calls from our tippers
请记住我们必须优先处理线人的电话
over the ones from the reporters.
而不是记者的电话
Now, back to your calls. I don't need your answer.
现在都回去接听电话吧 我不需要你们的回复
Hello?
喂？
-Yes. -That's right.
-是的 -没错
-Yes, from now on… -Is that right?
-是的 从现在起… -是那样吗？
-As for the case… -I'll take care of that.
-关于这起案子… -我会看着办的
The footage shows a man in a black jacket walking.
监控录像拍到了一个 穿着黑色夹克衫的行人的背影
He takes a look around, looking relaxed.
他向四周环顾了一圈 看起来很放松
The police have identified the man in the footage
警方已经确认录像中的该男子
as the prime suspect in the case.
是本案的首要嫌疑人
The jacket he is wearing matches the one that is missing from the scene.
他穿在身上的夹克衫 和在现场丢失的那件是一致的
And he was caught on this camera immediately after the incident took place.
而且在事故发生后不久 他就被这个监控摄像头拍下来了
According to the police, the size of this man's shoe print
据警方说 该男子的鞋印尺码
matches that of the shoe print
与谋杀老人案现场发现的
found at the scene of the senior citizen's murder.
足迹是匹配的
The MO seems similar as well,
作案手法看起来也很相似
so the possibility that the killer is the same person…
所以凶手是同一个人的可能性…
How are you feeling? Better?
你感觉如何？好点了吗？
Gosh, the commissioner was so mean to me.
天啊 厅长对我可太过分了
-Gosh. -Last night,
-真是的 -昨天晚上
when I went to his office to get his approval on the APB,
我去他办公室拿公开通缉令许可时
he kept hitting me on the back of the head,
他一直打我后脑勺
asking how we'll catch the killer with this alone.
还问我如何光凭这东西去抓人
I'm almost 50 now.
我也快50岁的人了
Gosh. He just can't quit that habit of his, can he?
真是的 他就不能改改他的习惯吗？
I stayed up all night and managed to persuade the commissioner,
我熬了一整晚想方设法说服厅长
but what will happen to us if this doesn't work?
可是如果这方法不奏效的话 我们会怎么样？
Well, it can't be undone now.
反正现在也无法挽回了
Don't be scared.
别害怕
Let's wait and see what happens.
让我们拭目以待会发生什么吧
The reporters are getting a thrill out of this.
记者们对此非常兴奋
They're watching us with their eyes peeled to see if we'll catch him
他们正密切注视着我们 看我们能否仅凭一张疑犯的背影照片
with this photo that shows nothing but his back.
就抓住人
Come on, Chief Heo. Why are you being like this?
拜托 许队长 你现在怎么这样了？
Are you suddenly regretting your decision?
你是突然后悔自己的决定了吗？
No, it's not that. I'm just frustrated. That's all.
倒不是后悔 我只是很郁闷罢了
It'd be amazing if we could catch that scumbag with this,
如果我们仅凭此就抓住了那个混蛋 那就太棒了
but it's also true it's more important to prevent more murders.
不过阻止更多谋杀案的发生更重要 这也是事实
You're right.
你说得没错
I already let him hit me in the head as if I were his punching bag.
这算什么 我连后脑勺都牺牲了
I don't care if I'm on the chopping block.
大不了再把脖子伸出去
-Let's go. -Okay, let's go.
-我们走 -好 我们走
I came to the right place.
我来对地方了
Aren't you from Gangnam Police Station? Wait.
你是江南警察局的吗？等一下
Was it Jongno Station?
是钟路警察局吗？
You are a detective, right? Oh, you must be from Seoul HQ.
你是刑警吧？ 你是从首尔总部过来的吧
Hello, I'm Reporter Choi Yoon-ji from Fact Today.
你好 我是来自 《今日真相》的记者崔润智
I have your business card.
我有你的名片
I knew it. We've met before, right?
是吧 我们之前见过吧？
Yes, Director.
喂 局长
I'm finally getting an exclusive report.
我终于能拿到独家报道了
You're interfering with official police duty.
你在妨碍警方执行公务
-What the heck? -Stop her.
-怎么回事？ -拦住她
There's no exclusive here.
没有独家新闻
What nonsense are you saying?
你在说什么啊？
Let me…
让我…
You're the cop who took my phone in front of the motel.
在汽车旅馆门口拿走我手机的警察
You are that cop, right? My gosh.
你是当时的那位
Goodness.
天啊
Detective, could you spare me a moment?
这位刑警 请问我能占用你一点时间吗？
I have many questions about this case.
关于这起案件 我有很多问题
The main road is over there.
那前面有一条主路
And this is the only security footage of him.
而这是他唯一的监控录像照片
I just think it's odd.
我只是觉得很奇怪
You put out an APB on a faceless suspect.
公开通缉一个没有露脸的疑犯
I don't get it.
我不明白
I can't tell you anything as we're still investigating the case.
由于案件尚在调查中 所以我什么都不能告诉你
Wait, Detective!
等一下 警察！
Can you at least tell me your name if I can't have your number?
如果你不给我你的电话号码的话 至少能告诉我你的名字吗？
He's leaving like that? What a petty jerk.
他就这么走了吗？真是个混蛋啊
That car…
那辆车…
SEOUL METROPOLITAN POLICE AGENCY
（首尔地方警察厅）
SERIAL MURDER GAME? WARNING TO SOCIETY OR TO POLICE?
（连环谋杀游戏？ 是对社会还是警方的警告？）
Kim Bong-sik, this jerk!
金奉植这个混蛋！
-That's it. -Nice shot.
-棒极了 -好球
MURDER SUSPECT WANTED REWARD 50 MILLION WON
（凶杀嫌犯通缉 悬赏5000万韩元）
Darn it, this punk…
见鬼 这个混蛋…
FACELESS SERIAL MURDER SUSPECT
（无脸的连环凶杀嫌疑犯）
What's the map for?
拿地图做什么？
I want to carry it around with me
我想随身带着它
when I visit the scenes for profiling purposes.
去现场做侧写
If I mark all the major bus and subway routes
如果我标记出所有公交车和 地铁的主路线
and note the time of each incident and even the weather that day,
并注明每次的案发时间 甚至是天气情况
it'll be helpful.
可能会有帮助
Then I'll help you.
我来帮你
Thank you.
谢谢
Hey, that's a lot of work.
喂 这工作量很大啊
I'm stating the obvious,
这不是很明显吗？
but the answers are always found at the scene.
答案总是在现场找到的
Shall I make you one too?
我要给你做一份吗？
No, it's okay. We'll share it.
不用了 我们共用一份就行
13 DAYS SINCE THE OPEN SEARCH BEGAN
（公开搜查后的第13天）
NOVEMBER 13, 2003
（2003年11月13号）
GUNGOK-DONG, HWANGHWA-DONG
（郡谷洞 黄花洞）
From here…
从这里…
It means he frequents this area via public transportation.
说明他乘坐大众交通工具 频繁出入这一带
All four cases
所有这四起案件
happened between 10 a.m. and 2 p.m.
都是在上午10点到下午2点间发生的
A timeframe when it's likely to find only women or the elderly at home.
是一个只有女人或老人 独自在家的时间
MEDICAL BOOKS
（医学书籍）
Are you looking for a particular book?
你在找什么书吗？
I'm looking for a book on anatomy.
我在找一本解刨学的书
I see. This way, please.
明白 请来这边
You can find them here.
你可以在这里找
If you have a particular title you're looking for,
如果你知道那本书的名字
I can look it up for you.
我可以直接帮你找出来
HUMAN ANATOMY
（《人类解剖学》）
ANATOMY
（《人类解剖学》《解剖学》）
It's already been over a month since you put out an APB.
你们公开通缉已经一个多月了
You still don't have anything for us?
还是对我们毫无交代吗？
At least tell us your lead.
至少告诉我们线索吧
Well, thankfully there hasn't been another victim yet.
庆幸的是目前没有新的谋杀案发生
We are doing everything we can.
我们正竭尽所能
You have to give us something
你得告诉我们点什么
so we can write an article.
否则就写不出报道了
Even after you put out the APB…
尽管你们发布了公开通缉后…
-At least share the information! -Tell us anything.
-至少公布点信息啊！ -告诉我们吧
Come on! Give me something to write about!
拜托！给我们点东西报道吧！
-Give us information. -Tell us!
-告诉我们消息！ -告诉我们！
Why won't you tell us?
为什么不告诉我们呢？
Please raise your hand and speak one at a time.
一个一个举手…
PROFILING REPORT
（分析报告）
I don't think now is the right time to hand this over.
我认为现在不是移交这个的时候
I know that too.
我也知道这个
I just think they really need a lead.
我只是觉得一点线索没有
I feel like there is a need
我感觉我们有必要
to examine and analyze the culprit's behavior
尽可能地分析检查罪犯的行为表现
as much as we can. Now more than ever.
现在比以往任何时候都需要这么做
It says here…
它这里说…
"Effort in trying to steal valuables is very low."
“偷窃贵重物品的意图很低”
What does this mean?
这是什么意思？
In the case of Hwanghwa-dong, there was an attempt to try to open the safe.
在黄花洞的案子中 罪犯曾企图打开保险箱
If stealing the valuables was his purpose,
如果他的目的是偷窃贵重物品
it only makes sense to kill the victim after he's made them open the safe.
在逼迫受害人打开保险箱后杀人 才说得通
But he did the opposite.
但他的所作所为恰恰相反
Above that, it says, "Character disorder severe enough
除此之外 上面还说 “严重到足以实施犯罪的人格障碍”
to commit a crime. Highly likely he had issues with family members."
“很可能有原生家庭问题”
Even if we can get his medical history, how can we know if he has issues at home?
没有他的病史 我们怎么知道 他是否有原生家庭问题呢？
For a person with this much rage,
对于一个如此愤怒的人
I'm sure that it showed in his daily life too.
我相信这也体现在他的日常生活中
We can't take a survey of every household though.
虽然我们不能挨家挨户地调查
It's not like we can ask
我们似乎不能询问
if they have a family member who has a lot of anger.
他们是否有极度暴怒的家庭成员
By the way, where is Chief Kim Bong-sik?
顺便问一句 金奉植股长在哪里？
He said he was going to the sauna.
他说过要去桑拿房的
My goodness.
我的天啊
Just how much dirt does he need to wash off?
他究竟有多少污垢要洗啊？
But here, it says, "The culprit's crimes,
但是这个 它说“凶手的犯罪行为
planning, and choice of location and time are too systematic.
布局及时间地点的选择都有条理
It's unlikely that he has an intellectual disability or schizophrenia.
他不像是有智力障碍或精神分裂
Therefore, there is a need to focus the investigation on people
因此我们很有必要调查
who have an aggressive character disorder."
那些有攻击性人格障碍的人”
I'm having trouble understanding this part.
我不太能理解这一部分
What's the reason we have to differentiate
我们为什么要区分
schizophrenia, intellectual disabilities, and character disorders?
精神分裂、智力障碍与人格障碍呢？
Character disorder is an illness when one shows extreme
人格障碍是指一个人表现出极端
or deformed forms of obsessive dependent, avoidant,
或畸形地强迫性依赖、回避
or antisocial characteristics.
或反社会特征
But everyone makes little of this illness
但是大家都不重视这种疾病
so they don't take active measures to treat it.
所以他们不会采取积极的措施 去治疗它
So there may not be medical records of it then.
因此很有可能没有相关的病史记录
Yes, that's right.
对 没错
Even if he did get treatment,
就算他得到过治疗
it probably didn't last long.
可能也不会持续太久
The possibility of having been admitted to a closed ward
因此住进封闭病房的可能性
is extremely low too.
也极其之低
Meaning character disorders don't leave many clues.
也就是说 人格障碍 不会留下太多线索
Are you sure it's not someone with an intellectual disorder or schizophrenia?
你确定他不是出于 精神分裂或智力障碍吗？
All right.
好吧
Let me explain this to you easily.
让我简单地给你们解释一下
Patients with schizophrenia, intellectual disorder, or delusion.
有精神分裂、智力障碍 或妄想症的病人
It's hard for them to commit premeditated crimes.
很难去实施有预谋的犯罪
You saw the crime scene of this case.
你看到过本案的犯罪现场
It's clean and there's no witness.
现场非常干净且没有目击证人
You're right. Cho Hyun Gil wasn't mentally ill either.
你说得对 赵贤吉也没有精神问题
What we're trying to tell you is
我们试图告诉你们的是
instead of mental patients who have been receiving continuous treatment,
尽管概率很低 我们还是应该寻找
although the chances are low,
有记录的人 将其列为嫌疑人
we should look for a suspect who has a record.
而不是那些一直在接受 持续性治疗的精神病患者
That's what we mean.
我们是这个意思
That means it will be harder to narrow down a suspect.
也就是说要确定嫌疑人就更难了
I thought you said you'd make it easier. I'm more confused now.
我以为你说你会让抓人变得更容易呢 我现在更迷糊了
That's too broad.
范围太宽了
We don't have enough people as is.
我们没有足够的人手
Based on what you're saying,
照你说的意思
every single citizen is a suspect then.
每一个市民都成嫌疑人了
To be blunt, who doesn't have a temper?
坦白说 谁没有脾气呢？
Besides our benevolent Superintendent Baek.
除了我们仁慈的白俊植科长
So these are more or less just guesswork.
所以这些或多或少只是猜测
Right?
对吗？
It's not like you gave us a specific lead that we can investigate on.
你并没有给我们一个 能够去精准调查的线索
We can't mobilize the entire squad just based on this.
我们不能仅凭此调动整个小队
It's been over three months
已经过去三个月了
and the police still don't have a single lead on the culprit.
警方还是没有任何关于罪犯的线索
He's a murderer who killed seven people.
他是谋杀了七条人命的凶手
You're talking as if the police are incompetent.
你这话听起来像是在控诉警方的无能
But they are doing their very best.
可是他们已经在竭尽全力了
That goes for the Hwanghwa-dong case from October too.
对于10月份黄花洞的案子也一样
They found an image of the culprit from CCTV footage.
他们从监控录像中找出了罪犯的人像
Also, they are actively receiving tip-offs
并且他们还在积极接受举报
so they will find a lead on the culprit soon.
很快会找到有关罪犯的线索的
It's already been over two months since they released an APB.
公开通缉已经有两个多月了
If they were relying on the APB for a lead they should've gotten one a long time ago.
如果他们靠公开通缉寻求线索的话 早就该找到了
Time is passing, including this moment here.
时间在流失 包括此时此刻
People are growing more anxious by the day.
人们也日渐变得焦虑
What do they plan on doing about this?
他们打算怎么处理此事？
To strengthen public security
为了加强公共安全
on top of increasing the number of patrolling officers,
除了增加巡逻人员数量以外
they have offered many solutions like installing security cameras
他们还提出了很多方案 比如在犯罪猖獗的地区
in crime-ridden districts.
加装监控摄像头
They are currently executing those solutions.
目前他们正在执行这些解决方案
DECEMBER 31, 2003
（2003年12月31号）
JANUARY 2, 2004
（2004年1月2号）
SUSEONG-DONG, JINJUNG-DONG
（寿城洞 晋中洞）
Seriously!
真是的！
-It's already been months! -What is this?
-已经好几个月了！ -这是什么呀？
He's a murderer. They only got a picture of his back.
他是凶手 他们只拍到了他的背影
How do they plan to catch him with this?
他们打算怎么用这个抓住他？
-Seriously. -That's what I mean!
-说正经的 -就是说啊！
-How can they catch him? -Seriously.
-他们要怎么抓住他啊？ -真是的
Gosh, he's an evil one, isn't he?
天啊 他太坏了吧？
-Yes. -You're right.
-是的 -你说得对
Why can't they catch him?
为什么他们抓不住他？
-What are the police doing? -Exactly.
-警察都在干什么？ -就是
They still haven't been able to catch a punk like this.
他们还是没能抓到这样的混蛋
-I know right? -Yes.
-我说对吧？ -嗯
Next up.
下一则消息
It's been over three months since the police released
距警方发布一张嫌犯背影照片
an APB with a picture of the suspect's back.
公开通缉已经过去三个多月了
This serial murder case of rich, elderly citizens
去年10月这一谋杀富有老人
shocked the nation last October.
连环杀人案震惊了全国上下
They still haven't been able to catch the suspect yet.
可到现在他们都没能抓到嫌犯
Inspector Song or whatever is nowhere to be found.
我们也找不到宋警卫等人
I can't find anything.
我这里一点发现都没有
It's been reported to us.
已经有人向我们报告了
Simultaneously, the police continue to look for the suspect…
与此同时警方还在继续搜捕疑犯…
I don't even know anymore.
我都不知道了
They stated…
他们说…
-I'll write one up quickly. -No, it's fine.
-我会马上写一篇出来的 -不用 没关系
Captain.
组长
Take a look at this.
你快来看
The decision for an open search.
公开通缉决定
Is this the police's lifeline or is this the beginning of doom?
这是警察的救命稻草 还是厄运的开始？
FACT TODAY, REPORTER CHOI YOON-JI
（《今日真相》记者崔润智）
If the culprit does not stop
如果罪犯没有收手
and continues to commit the crimes in hiding,
躲起来继续做案的话
it might turn into a bad move that'll lead to difficulty
对于找出真凶一事
in finding leads to the culprit.
反而会起到反效果
The murders broke out four times, not just once.
谋杀案发生了四次而不是一次
How can they not catch the culprit?
他们怎么就抓不到罪犯呢？
The pathetic reality of the police.
警察的可悲现实啊
-Just as I expected of the police. -When will they catch the culprit?
-我对警察就没抱太大希望 -他们什么时候才能抓住罪犯？
I'm too scared.
我太害怕了
The culprit will definitely kill someone again.
罪犯一定还会杀人的
It was too rash to start an open search.
开展公开通缉实在太鲁莽了
The culprit would only hide more.
罪犯只会藏得更深
I'd trust my dog before I trust the police.
我家的狗都比警察更可靠
You wanted to make the Behavioral Analysis Team,
犯罪行为分析组是你们想要组建的
so I let you have your way, but what have you done right?
所以我批准了 可你们做了些什么？
You began an open search just by using a photo of his back,
你们拿一张背影照片就开始公开搜查
but you have no evidence?
就没有别的线索了吗？
This only made the police look ridiculous!
这样只会让警方看起来很荒谬！
How will you patch this up?
你们要如何弥补此事？
Commissioner.
厅长
Our detectives are out there running around and doing their best.
我们刑警正在外面竭尽全力搜捕
And so is the Behavioral Analysis Team.
犯罪行为分析组也在全力以赴
I don't want your best!
我不要你们的全力以赴！
Bring me the result!
我要的是结果！
Bring that jerk who killed seven people immediately!
马上把那个杀了七个人的混蛋 给我带过来
Put him before those wordy reporters!
把他带去那些喋喋不休的记者面前！
When you were out on the field,
您在现场的时候
you taught us a few ways, and we tried everything.
教我们那些方法 我们都试过了
We asked around the crime scene,
我们在犯罪现场四周做了调查
we talked to every deliveryman around the area.
该地区的每个快递员我们都找过了
We searched every Internet cafe user in the area.
那里的每个网咖我们也都搜查了
We even got a warrant to search the base station,
我们甚至申请了基站的搜查令
and searched every person who used their phones in the area.
并搜索了每个在那里用过手机的人
But we still haven't found a strand of the culprit's hair.
可我们还是连罪犯的一撮头发 都没找到
The Behavioral Analysis Team or whoever, we need to ask
不管是犯罪行为分析组还是其他人
and find a new method
我们都得寻找调查这起案件的
of investigating this case.
新方法了
Yes, so just as the Analysis Team reported on the profiling report,
对 所以正如犯罪行为分析组在 分析报告上所说的那样
we plan on searching for people with mental illnesses
我们计划搜索那些在调查过程中
who have sought help along with the investigation.
寻求帮助的精神疾病患者
Darn it.
该死的
You didn't know that I've been getting reports
你们不知道有人报告我说
that the Analysis Team is out on the field, did you?
犯罪行为分析组的人也在现场 对吗？
-Sorry? -They keep asking me
-什么？ -他们一直问我
who those guys are and complaining about them.
他们是什么人 还一直跟我抱怨他们
I can only turn a blind eye to those complaints for so long.
睁一只眼闭一只眼也是有限度的
We can't force them to stop when they want to take part
他们想要介入调查的话
in the investigation.
我们很难阻止
Enough.
够了
I don't want to hear your excuses anymore.
我不想再听你们的借口了
Make sure you take firm measures.
确保你采取会强硬措施
-Yes, sir.
-明白
What is it you want to say?
你到底想说什么把氛围搞成这样？
What is it?
怎么说？
Let's put an end to our obsession.
我们别执着了吧
The SCS has too many cases to resolve
机搜队还有很多案子要办呢
rather than look for some guy who can't even be detected.
而不是一味搜查一个 根本无法被找到的家伙
You talk as if we're a huge burden to the Special Crime Squad.
你这话说的好像 我们是机搜队的累赘一样
You never even bother to hear us out.
你都懒得听我们把话说完
Young-soo, that's not what happened.
荣秀 你把话说清楚
We began an open search for him just with a photo of his back.
我们仅凭他的一张背影照片 就开始了公开搜查
The commissioner taught me a big lesson when I went in
我去申请批准文件的时候
to have some documents approved.
厅长给我上了一课
-So you called us to nitpick over that? -Nitpick? I'm your superior.
-所以你叫我们来是为了追究这个？ -追究？我是你上司
Why would I do that with you two?
我为什么要找你俩做那些？
If anything, I'd give you an order.
还不如给你们下命令呢
All I'm saying is that we've all done enough.
我只是说我们做得够多了
What do you mean by enough? Are you telling us to give up?
你说的够多是什么意思？ 你在叫我们放弃吗？
Hey, there is no giving up when it comes to our cases.
我们是不会放弃任何案子的
I'm saying there are many cases we could solve with that time.
我是说有那个时间 我们可以办掉很多案子的
Come on.
拜托
We never just sat on our hands.
我们从来没有闲下来过
The Behavioral Analysis Team has done our duty by ourselves.
犯罪行为分析组已经竭尽全力了
What is it? Stop beating around the bush and tell me.
你是什么意思？别再拐弯抹角 就直接告诉我吧
Goodness.
天啊
I'll be frank.
那我就老实说了
Those up above aren't happy
上面的人对犯罪行为分析组
with the Behavioral Analysis Team.
不是很满意
They were never happy with us. Good grief.
他们就没有对我们满意过 真是的
We're a workplace. An organization. What can we do?
这里是工作场合 是一个机构 我们能怎么办呢？
Those men out there also are complaining
那些外面的人还在抱怨
about how your team is coming in and out of the crime scenes.
你们组的人怎么能随便进出犯罪现场
The only thing we can do is investigate the crime scene.
我们唯一能做的就是调查犯罪现场啊
-If you stop us from doing that… -I mean,
-如果你不让我们那么做… -我是说
I just want to stop by the crime scene after the forensics are done.
我只是想在取证结束后 去一趟犯罪现场
What's the problem?
有什么不妥吗？
There are many other things you can work on.
还有别的很多事你们可以做啊
You know, those documents you took from the cabinets.
那些储藏柜上的文件
You all study that and create data too.
你也都研究过 还整理了数据
That's our job, so we'll manage, okay?
那是我们的工作 我们会看着办的好吗？
Please don't stop us from going to the crime scenes.
请不要阻止我们去犯罪现场
There's nothing he can do to stop us. We can go whenever we want to.
他阻止不了我们 我们可以想去哪里就去哪里
Forget it. I'm done with this. Goodbye.
得了 我不想多说了 再见
We need to put an end to this. Inspector Song.
我们得结束这一切了 宋警卫
I know you visit the crime scene every day.
我知道你每天都去查看犯罪现场
I'm not trying to stop you.
我没有在试图阻止你
Please use your effort on something else too.
也请你花点时间在别的事情上吧
Let's go.
我们走
I'm talking to him right now.
我正在跟他说话
It's my first time having a serious talk with him.
这是我第一次这么严肃地跟他谈话
You don't have to listen. There's nothing serious about it.
你不必非得听这些 没什么要紧的
Come on out.
出来吧
That little…
这个疯子…
Please excuse me.
请回吧
You understand what I mean, right?
你明白我的意思吧？
-What now? -What do you mean?
-现在怎么办？ -什么怎么办？
I would've never started if I was going to stop.
如果我会停下来的话就不会开始了
Do you know something we have in common?
你知道我俩的共同点是什么吗？
-Nothing. -Exactly.
-没有吧 -正是
Who do they think we are?
他们以为我们是谁？
Let's not lose our spirit. We have lots to do.
不要丧失信心 我们要做的还有很多
Mr. Gu Young-chun, please come on in.
顾永春先生 请进来吧
X-RAY ROOM
（X光室）
Sir, we're about to take an X-ray of your entire body.
患者 我们要开始为您的全身 照射X光射线了
64 DAYS SINCE THE OPEN SEARCH BEGAN
（公开搜查后的第64天）
JANUARY 3, 2004
（2004年1月3号）
Did he give up on committing another crime to hide?
他是放弃作案躲起来了吗？
Or…
还是…
is he still planning another crime?
他仍在计划一次新的作案？
You never miss a day.
你一天都不落下啊
We never know when the crimes will start again.
我们永远都不知道 犯罪会在什么时候发生
Don't believe…
不要想着…
that you decided to begin the open search all by yourself.
是你独自决定开展公开搜查的
The Special Crime Squad isn't incompetent
机搜队还没有无能到
to the point we'd blindly follow
让我们所有人都盲目跟着
a rash decision.
做出草率决定的地步
From the outside,
从外界看来
it may seem like the investigation is standing still.
调查似乎停滞不前
Until the moment we catch the culprit,
直到我们抓到罪犯的那一刻
even we sometimes feel that way.
有时候连我们自己都会怀疑
However,
但是
we came to this choice altogether.
这个选择是我们共同做出的
What doesn't change is how we came to the same decision.
我们是如何共同做出决定的事实 不会改变
That all we want is to catch the culprit.
我们只想抓到罪犯
What's more important than wanting to catch the culprit
比想抓到罪犯更重要的是
is actually catching the culprit.
事实上我们正在追捕他
We will catch him. Certainly.
我们会抓到他的 一定会的
He will not stop.
他不会收手的
We'll catch him before he goes on.
我们会在他继续行动前抓到他
I thought it would work once we stopped him.
我以为只要我们能阻止他就成功了
I look through the daily reports every morning,
每天早上我都会看日报
and I don't see a report of a crime in that same pattern.
但我没见过类似的犯罪报告
What if…
如果…
What if the culprit changed the MO?
如果罪犯改变了作案手法呢？
What do we do then?
那我们该如何是好？
DAILY CASE REPORT
（每日案件报告）
JANUARY 30, 2004 VICTIM: KIM YANG-HEE
（2004年1月30号 被害人金洋熙）
THE VICTIM WAS STABBED WITH A CAMPING KNIFE
（被害人被一把野营用刀刺伤）
-Go home. -See you later.
-回家吧 -再见
-Call me. -Text me.
-给我电话哦 -记得给我发消息
-Hurry. It's getting cold. -Okay, bye.
-快走吧 太冷了 -好的 再见
-Call me.
-给我打电话 -好 再见
FEBRUARY 12, 2004
（2004年2月12号）
SINHEUNG 2-DONG, YEONGDEUNGPO-GU
（新兴二洞 永登浦区）
Are you home?
你到家了吗？
I'm almost home.
我快到了
TO SU-MIN
（收信人 秀敏）
The devil has yet again disappeared without a trace.
魔鬼又消失得无影无踪了
Time is ticking.
时间在一分一秒地过去
If this becomes a cold case…
如果案子变成悬案的话…
Most murderers like him usually kill for their own pleasure and enjoyment.
大多数像他那样的杀人犯 杀人都是为了自己的快乐享受
It means killing makes them happy.
这意味着杀人能使他们快乐
-Camping knife? -Do you think it's the same guy?
-野营用刀？ -你觉得会是同一个家伙吗？
It's similar to the guy we're looking for.
这和我们在找的人很相似
The murder weapon, MO, and time don't match at all.
凶器、作案手法和时间都完全不一样
What if it's what we speculated?
如果就像我们所推测的那样呢？
What if he failed to finish the job?
是因为他失手了呢？
Then we have two serial killers in this country.
那么我们这个国家 就有两个连环杀人犯了